Unit one, Dialogue one. Robert Smith is met by Murugan on his arrival at Chennai airport.
வணக்கம். நீங்க ராபர்ட் ஸ்மித்தா?
(vaṇakkam. niinga raabaṭ smittaa?)
Greetings. Are you Robert Smith?
ஆமா, நான்தான் ராபர்ட் ஸ்மித். வணக்கம்.
(aamaa, naandaan raabaṭ smit. vaṇakkam.)
என் பேரு முருகன். பேராசிரியர் மதிவாணனோட மாணவன்.
(en peeru murugan. peeraasiriyar madivaaṇanooḍa maaṇavan.)
My name is Murugan. Professor Madhivanan’s student.
ரொம்ப மகிழ்ச்சி.
(romba magiẓcci.)
Pleased to meet you. (lit. Much pleasure)
வாங்க ஹோட்டலுக்கு போவோம். அங்க கொஞ்சம் ஓய்வு எடுங்க.
(vaanga hooṭṭalukku poovoom. anga konjam ooyvu eḍunga.)
Come. Let’s go to the hotel. You can rest up a bit.
(lit. Take some rest there)
சரி, வாங்க போவோம்.
(sari, vaanga poovoom.)
Fine. Come, let’s go.
Now practice a few of the words in the dialogue on their own by repeating them after the speaker.
வணக்கம் (vaṇakkam)
பேரு (peeru)
பேராசிரியர் (peeraasiriyar)
மாணவன் (maaṇavan)
வா (vaa)
ஓட்டல் (ooṭṭal)
அங்கே (angee)
போ (poo)
கொஞ்சம் (konjam)
ஓய்வு (ooyvu)
எடு (eḍu)
The dialogue shows two ways of giving a person's name. The first is:
நான் ஸ்மித் (naan smit)
I am Smith.
The second is:
என் பேரு ஸ்மித் (en peeru smit)
My name is Smith. You will note that in neither case is there a verb 'to be' in Tamil.
When the speaker gives an example of the first type, give the corresponding second form during the pause.
நான் முருகன் (naan murugan)
என் பேரு முருகன் (en peeru murugan)
பேராசிரியர் மதிவாணன் (peeraasiriyar madivaaṇan)
பேராசிரியர் பேரு மதிவாணன் (peeraasiriyar peeru madivaaṇan)
மாணவன் ராமு (maaṇavan raamu)
மாணவன் பேரு ராமு (maaṇavan peeru raamu)